嘿，你们好，我是TheCherno，欢迎回到我的游戏引擎系列
hey guys, my name is TheCherno, welcome back to my game engine series
那么上期我们介绍了渲染，如果你们还没看过那期，一定要去看看
so the last time we took a look at an introduction to rendering, definitely check that video out, if you haven't already
因为今天我们会继续讨论上期剩下的东西
because today we're gonna continue off, kind of where we left off in that video
实际上就是讨论这整个渲染的架构，以及我们渲染图形的所有问题
and actually talk about the architecture of this whole renderer, and just the whole problem of we need to render graphics of the screen
比如我们如何在引擎中实现那个，正如我承诺的那样，确实准备了一些PPT
how do we do that in an engine, as promised I did prepare a little bit of a powerpoint presentation
那应该很酷，那我们就直接去看看那个吧
which should be pretty cool, so we're gonna jump in that, into that in just a second
但我只是想先说，首先，非常感谢所有让这一系列成为可能的赞助人
but I just want to kind of start off by just saying, first of all, huge thank you to all of the patreons that make this series possible
就是patreon.com/thecherno，谢谢你们的支持对我来说意义重大，尤其是现在，因为太忙了
patreon.com/thecherno, thank your support just means the world to me, especially right now, because I'm so busy
我仍然希望能够为你们播放这些视频，你们已经看到人们
and I still want to be able to pump out these videos for you guys, and you've seen that people are
所以对支持这一系列的兴趣对我来说绝对是惊喜
so interested in supportive of this series is absolutely amazing to me
如果你们有兴趣成为赞助人，一定要看看那个链接
if you're interested in becoming a patreon, definitely check out that link
你们会收到些奖励，比如提前收到视频，尽管那在目前还没实现，因为我的生活太疯狂了
you'll receive a bunch of rewards such as videos early, although that's kind of unhold at the moment since my life is so crazy
但你们可以访问诸如Hazel引擎的源代码之类的，这些源代码基本上已经像提前编写的那样了
but you'll get access to things like source code for Hazel engine that has already been like way way way written in in advance essentially
所以我们现在讨论的这类东西已经实现了，并且在分支中是可用的
so this kind of stuff that we're covering now has somewhat been implemented already, and is a little usable in a branch
就像是一种方法，让它变得更像一个，我想更多的控制，让Hazel能够朝着正确的方向前进
and just kind of as like as a way to kind of get more of like a, I guess more control into where Hazel actually going being able to steer it into the right direction
我通常也会在discord和与Hazel的开发相关的赞助频道上发布内容
I commonly post things on discord as well and the patrons channel relating to Hazel's development
当我写代码时，就像写开发博客一样，我有时会尝试做那些
as I write the code and like it's almost like a development blog, at times I try and do that
只是为了让你们了解我正在做的事情
just to keep you guys updated with what I'm actually working on
因为很明显，我是独立地在Hazel上工作的，然后我最终会在以后的时间里实现
because obviously I work on Hazel kind of independently, and then eventually what I kind of implement eventually way away later in the future
很明显，在这些视频中，我详细地解释了我正在做的
makes its way to videos such as this one, and obviously in these videos, I explain what I'm doing a lot more
然后讨论我们将如何构建某些东西，无论如何，关于渲染架构，让我们直接深入吧
and talk about like how we're gonna structure certain things, anyway, rendering architecture, let's dive in
好了，在Hazel引擎中渲染架构，首先，漂亮的背景不是在Hazel中渲染的
okay, so rendering architecture in the Hazel engine, first of all, that beautiful background is not rendered in Hazel
那是我在澳大利亚维多利亚州南部拍摄的照片
that's actually a photo I took in pretty much the south of victoria here in Australia
如果你们想看更多我的照片，就去访问instagram.com/thechernol吧，描述里面有
if you wanted to see more of my photos, instagram.com/thechernol, it will be a link in the description
因为我也喜欢摄影，但也许有一天，我们可以在Hazel上渲染出这样的东西
because I do love photography as well, but maybe one day, we can render something like this in Hazel
那将是一个非常好的目标，一个非常好的目标，不管怎样，整个事情都有两面性
that would be quite nice, quite a good goal to aim for, anyway, there were two sides to this whole thing
我想我应该谈谈的一件事，我的意思是在渲染视频的介绍中，我涵盖了很多内容
and I guess one of the things that I should probably talk about, I mean in the introduction to rendering video, I did cover a lot
我真的不想有太多重复，所以我们现在要采取更实际的方法
and I don't want to really overlap too much, so we're gonna do taking more of a practical approach at this now
但实际上，我认为游戏引擎中的渲染系统有两个方面
but effectively the way that I kind of see this is there are two sides to a rendering system in a game engine
有一种叫做渲染接口的东西，这个术语也是我最终编出来的
there's something called the render api, which again this terminology is something that I eventually made up
我的意思是，这显然是有道理的，其他人过去也用过，而且确实用过
I mean it does make sense obviously, and other people have used it in the past, and do use it
但这与一些教科书或类似的东西不同，所以不要期望，但本质上我们拥有的是一个渲染接口
but this isn't like from some textbook or anything like that, so don't expect that, but essentially what we have is a render api
这是平台和api渲染api图形api，我们正在构建的整个系统的特定部分，那意味着
which is the platform and api render api graphics api, specific part of this whole system that we're building, what that means is that
这实际上是特定于OpenGL，特定于Vulcan，特定于DirectX，这是一种
this is actually specific to OpenGL, specific to Vulcan, specific to DirectX, this is this kind of
这边的这部分实际上是我们与那些平台或接口结合在一起的东西，而这部分我们将接触
this side of this line is stuff that we actually tie into those platforms or those apis, whereas this side which we'll get into
一旦我们通过所有这些要点，我们将在未来接触
which we'll get into kind of in the future, once we get through all of these points
这将类似于渲染，有点像接口，平台无关的那种，有点像这两者的这一面
this is going to be like the render, kind of the api platform independent, kind of side of this side of these two
这两个方面，系统的两个方面，让我们看看我们得到了什么，所以渲染上下文，对吧
two sides side of these, two sides of the system, so let's take a look at what we've got, so render context, right
这方面也是，这是一个实现，就像在OpenGL或Vulcan中一样
so again this side, what this is is, it's an implementation that is implemented like in OpenGL or in Vulcan
那些实际的接口，这是我们必须基本上按照接口实现的特定内容，这也是没有办法的，对吧
those actual apis, this is the stuff that is specific that we have to basically implement per api, there's no way around that, right
所以我们基本上要构建什么，对吧，所以我们构建渲染上下文，交换链和帧缓冲区之类的
so we have essentially what do we build, right, so we build a render context, we build things like a swap chain a frame buffer
顶点缓冲区可能更容易一次列出所有这些，一个索引缓冲区
a vertex buffer might just be easier to just list all these I think, at once an index buffer
你们知道的，纹理，着色器，状态，管道和渲染过程，然后我们会转到下一个方面
you know, texture kind of api, shader api, states, pipelines, render passes, and then we'll kind of move on to the next side
让我们来讨论一下，我的意思是，这些基本上是
so let's talk about this for a bit, what I mean by this is that the these are essentially in a way
我想你们可以把它们称为渲染接口原语，我可能错过了很多东西
I guess you could call them render api primitives, and I've probably missed like a bunch of things
这就像是我脑海中一个松散的列表，但本质上我们需要
this is just like a loose kind of off the top of my head kind of list, but essentially we need to if we're like
正如你们在下一张幻灯片中所看到的那样，我们将从实现OpenGL开始
and the way that we're gonna start this out as you'll see in the next slide is by implementing OpenGL
因此，如果我们以它为例，对吧
so if we use that as an example, right
我们需要做的基本上是创建，你们可以看到这些东西中的每一个都有一个类
what we need to do is essentially make, you could see a class for each of these things
但本质上是OpenGL的一个实现，就像这个渲染上下文，交换链，帧和顶点缓冲，下个缓冲
but essentially an implementation for OpenGL, for like this render context, this swap chain, this frame buffer, the vertex buffer the next buffer
因为这是一种渲染原语，从中我们可以告诉显卡我们要做什么
because these are kind of render primitives out of which we tell our graphics card what it is we want to do
对吧，比如顶点缓冲区，对，我们有一个数据缓冲区，我们想要它，把它发送到GPU
right, so things like a vertex buffer, right, we have a buffer of data, we want it, send it into the GPU
然后实际上能够使用它，可能是静态的，可能是动态的，然而我们想用它，对吧
and then actually be able to use it, maybe like kind of statically, maybe dynamically, however we want to use that, right
我们需要个接口来实现那个，最酷的是我们在每个接口中都实现了这一点
we need an api to be able to do that, and the cool thing about this is that we implement this in every api
所以在其他方面，我们会有一个OpenGL的实现，我们会有一个Vulcan的实现，对吧
so in other ways, we'd have an implementation for OpenGL, we would have an implementation for Vulcan, right
一旦我们有了它，我们实际上可以从渲染器的角度不可知地使用它，对吧
and then once we have that, we can actually use it from the renderer side of things agnostically, right
这意味着我们有一个渲染实现，它只是说
which means that it doesn't matter we have one implementation of the render, which just says
好了，首先在交换链中创建渲染上下文，然后创建实际渲染可能需要的任何帧缓冲区
okay, first up create a render contacts in a swap chain, then you know, create any frame buffers, you might need for actual rendering
然后我想渲染一个三角形，让我们上传一些顶点缓冲区数据和一些索引缓冲区数据
then I want to render a triangle, so let's upload some vertex buffer data and some index buffer data
当然我们要创建一个着色器
and we're going to create a shader of course
然后我们将创建一个渲染过程或管道或任何我们需要的东西，然后开始渲染该三角形
and then we'll create a render pass or a pipeline or anything else we need, and then we'll kick off rendering that triangle
对吧，就是那样，好了，但问题是要渲染一个三角形，我们使用渲染器中的这个渲染接口
right, that's it, okay, but the thing is to render a triangle, we use this render api from the renderer
很酷的是，如果突然决定，我们实际上会减少使用Vulcan或DirectX12或其他工具的渲染
and the cool thing about this is that suddenly if we decide, we'll actually less render using Vulcan or DirectX12 or whatever
这一部分显然是包含这些接口的实际实现的部分，但这一部分没有改变
this part obviously is the part that contains the actual implementation of those apis, but this part does not change
我们只需要监听一个开关，好了，现在在DirectX12中执行，但是我们绘制三角形的逻辑
we just have to hear a switch that says okay, now do it in DirectX12, but our logic for drawing a triangle
我们传入的实际渲染命令本质上是相同的
our actual render commands that we pass in are essentially going to be the same
现在在上期视频中，在渲染视频的介绍中，我谈到了如何很难划清界限
now in the last video, in the introduction to rendering video, I talked about how it was really hard to kind of draw the line
这是条线，这是我刚才说的线，我画了那条界限，我说过这是在这边
and this is the line, this is the line I was talking about, I've drawn that line, and I've said this is on this side
这是在这一边，对吧，但现在你们实际上可以看到什么实际上属于每一边
this is on this side, right, but now you actually kind of see what actually belongs to each kind of side
如果我想突然给三角形添加纹理，对吧，我该怎么办
again if I want to suddenly add a texture to a triangle, right, what do I do
我只是说，好吧，让我们加载一个纹理并绑定它，然后我们将使用该纹理进行绘制，对吧
I just say okay, let's load a texture and bind it, and we'll draw using that texture, right
我们将很明显地更新着色器代码，以实际从该纹理采样，然后绘制这些像素
and we'll update the shader code obviously to actually sample from that texture and then draw those pixels
但是我们如何使用这个纹理，我们只是说，哦，我们想创建一个纹理
but how do we use that texture, we just say, oh we wanna make a texture
对吧，至于实现细节，好吧，它到底意味着什么
right, the implementation details of, okay, what does it even mean
我想创建一个纹理，你们知道，我要从文件中读取它，然后我该怎么处理这些数据，对吧
I wanna make a texture, you know, I'm going to read that from a file, and then what am I gonna do with that data, right
这是由DirectX12或Vulcan OpenGL或其他什么工具实现的吗？那就在线这边，对吧
is that going to be implemented by DirectX12 or Vulcan OpenGL or whatever, that is on this side of the line, right
因此，这只是一个接口，它为我们提供了对这种低级代码的访问
so this is just an api that provides us access to that kind of lower level code
但是我们在渲染器中使用这个接口来实际渲染我们想要的，好吧，那样做的好处显然是
but then we use this api in our renderer to actually render what we want, okay, and the benefit of that obviously is that
我们在幕后使用什么接口并不重要，就像我们在所有其他接口之上创建另一个接口一样
it doesn't matter what api we use under the hood, it's kind of like we're creating another api on top of all those other apis
这正是我们想要的，你们知道，通常要简单得多
it's going to do exactly what we want, you know, much much much simpler way usually
然后所有的努力都是在幕后完成的，对吧，那就是整个想法
and then all the hard work is kind of done behind the scenes, right, that's kind of the whole idea
让我们看一下渲染器将负责的事情，因此实际的2D和3D渲染器
so let's take a look at things that the renderer would be responsible for, so the actual 2D & 3D renderer
之前的做法是否会推迟，那将在很大程度上得到实现，使用的是来自此的实际原始类型
whether that before would deferred whatever, that is going to be implemented largely, using actual kind of primities from this
现在我必须提到的是，接口之间存在着分歧，就像我刚才说的上期那样，哦，这太难了
now I have to mention that, there are differences in the api, like I didn't just say last episode that, oh this is gonna be so hard
做这件事总是很难，然后我觉得那很容易，我们要举起来，我要列出所有这些的关键点
it's always so hard to do this, and then here I'm like that's easy, we're just gonna lift up, I'm gonna list all these dog points
我们会这样那样做，一切都会很美好，不，因为你们知道在OpenGL中实现延迟渲染
we're gonna do this and that, everything's gonna be sweet, no, because you know implementing a deferred render in OpenGL
与像Vulcan这样的东西不同，因为在Vulcan中，这些原语的数量比在OpenGL中要多
versus something like Vulcan it's different, because in Vulcan, you just have kind of more of these primitives than you do in OpenGL
在OpenGL中，你们只需要创建一组帧缓冲区，就是那样，而在Vulcan中
in OpenGL, you just kind of create like a bunch of frame buffers, and that's kind of it, whereas in Vulcan
你们知道你们可以有管道和描述符集之类的东西，还有更多的实际内容
and you know you can have things like pipelines and like descriptor sets, and just more kind of just more actual content for this
这就是为什么我不能，OpenGL与Vulcan DirectX12完全不同
which is why something like I can't, OpenGL is something completely different to like Vulcan DirectX12
因为这是正确的，就像某些高级渲染技术的方法实际上是完全不同的
because it is right like the approach to some of these advanced rendering techniques is actually quite different
所以当我们进入延迟渲染，甚至是基于平铺的渲染或诸如此类的事情时，这将是很有趣的
so it's going to be interesting, when we get into things like deferred rendering or even like tile based rendering or anything like that
对吧，因为我们设置它的方式实际上可能不同，我们可能需要扩展这个渲染接口
right, because the way that we kind of set this up might actually differ, and we might have to extend this render api
基本上，只要我们需要编写更多的Vulcan代码，就可以使用这些原语
and basically whenever we need to just write more Vulcan code than otherwise possible with these primitives
因为我们需要一种更有效的延迟渲染方法，例如，因为你们可以使用这些原语实现延迟渲染
because we want a more efficient way of deferred rendering, for example, because you can achieve deferred rendering with these primitives
那很好，但是Vulcan可能有更好的方法，通过使用更多的控制
that's fine, but Vulcan might have a better way of doing it by using more control essentially
很明显，Vulcan有一些东西
and obviously Vulcan has things
比如你们知道的看到同步原语，比如栅栏和信号量之类的东西，对吧
like you know seeing the synchronization primitives like fences and semaphores and that kind of stuff, right
不是OpenGL真正拥有的东西，所以会有一些不同，不会像这看起来那么简单
not something OpenGL really has, so there's gonna be some difference, there's not gonna be a straightforward as this might look
因为我不想让你们认为我在上一期里表现得太难了
because I don't want you guys to think that I've made it out to be so hard in the last episode and inside the lamb, just like that
这很容易，不容易，我只是为你们简化一下，这样我们就可以开始实现这个了
it's gonna be easy, it's not gonna be easy, I'm just simplifying it for you guys, so that we can actually start doing this
这样你们就不会觉得不知所措，但可能会觉得有点不知所措
and so that you don't feel two overwhelmed, but maybe feel a little bit overwhelmed
只是因为我不想让事情变得更简单，所以正因为如此
just because I don't want to like make this out to be actually more simple than it is, so because of that yeah
就像我们可能不得不说的那样，你们知道仅仅用这些实现延迟渲染器没有什么意义
like we might have to say, well you know what it doesn't make sense to have a deferred renderer implemented with just these
就像平台和接口不可知原语一样，那可能没有任何意义，那完全没问题
like platform and api agnostic primitives, that might not make any sense, and that's totally fine
因为接下来我们要做的是将代码的这一部分移动到渲染接口区域，现在的缺点是
because then what we'll do is we'll move that part of the code into the render api zone, now the downside the drop that
通常情况下，当你们做出决策时，事情会变得更有效率，但你们突然有了更多的代码
usually what happens when you make that decision is things get more efficient, but you suddenly have more code
因为突然之间，任何明显移动到渲染接口区域的内容都需要按照接口实现
because suddenly anything you move obviously into the render api zone needs to be implemented per api
因此，我们突然需要为Vulcan的OpenGL提供延迟渲染或任何实现
so we need to suddenly have a deferred rendering or whatever implementation for OpenGL for Vulcan
从我们实际选择支持的任何接口（我们有点想避免），显然我们真正想做的是
from whatever apis we actually choose to support, which we kind of want to avoid, obviously what we actually want to do is
尝试在平台和接口的代码部分中使用尽可能多的代码
try and have as much code as possible in that platform and api agnostic kind of section of our code
因为那意味着我们不必每次都有单独的实现
because that means that we don't have to have a separate implementation every time we want to do that
一般来说，我们之所以有这个，这似乎是一个愚蠢的问题
the reason we have this line in general, this might seem like a silly question
但我知道有些人可能有点困惑我们之所以有这个界线是因为
but I know some people might be a little bit confused the reason why we have this line is because
再次回想一下渲染三角形，我们是否希望每个接口编写四次或五次代码
again think back to rendering a triangle, do we want to write code four or five times per api
如果我们有DirectX12，如果我们有Vulcan，如果我们有OpenGL，如果我们有Metal
if we have like DirectX12, if we have Vulcan, if we have OpenGL, if we have Metal
不管我们想写什么代码来为每个接口呈现一个三角形，不，我们想做的是创建所有这些图元
whatever do we want to write code to render a triangle for each api, no, what we want to do is create all these primitives
然后，正如我所描述的，我们将在文本显示中创建顶点缓冲区和索引缓冲区
and then as I kind of described, you know, we'll create a vertex buffer and an index buffer in a text show
你们知道的，关于着色器，无论需要什么，我们都会创建它
you know shader whatever we need, we create that
然后就像绘制三角形的代码一样，Hazel很容易处理，对吧
and then like the the code to draw a triangle is just easily handled by Hazel, right
然后通过那种方式进入所有这些接口，因此我们只需要编写一次代码
and then that kind of branches off into all those api, so that we really only need to write that code once
我们想渲染一个三角形，这是渲染三角形的代码，我们只写一次
we want to render a triangle, this is the code to render a triangle, we've write at once
然后它就像你们知道的，越来越底层时，就会访问到指定接口
and then it kind of you know will eventually lower lower and low level as it kind of goes down into the api
你们知道的，它最终会使用OpenGL或DirectX12等任何渲染接口方式
it will eventually hit, you know, whatever render api way using such as OpenGL or DirectX12
不管怎样，让我们回到渲染器这件事上来，就像场景，对吧，就像个场景管理器
anyway let's get back into this renderer thing, so things like a scene graph, right, like a scene manager
那不是你们通常会用到的，不想在那种情况下写原始OpenGL代码，比如在那种系统中
that's not something you usually have in, you don't want to write raw OpenGL code kind of in that, like for that kind of system
这是你们知道的，它与实际的渲染接口没有任何关系，你们知道，比如排序
it's something that is you know, it doesn't have anything to do with actual rendering apis, you know, you have like sorting
是吧，决定渲染什么，在设置其他内容后可能需要渲染某些内容，因为混合之类的事情
right, deciding what to render, when some things might need to be rendered after setting other things, because of things like blending
但我们通常也希望能够将使用相同材质、相同着色器或相同纹理的对象排序在一起
but also we typically want to be able to sort things that use the same material or the same shader or the same texture, kind of together
所以我们不需要像剔除那样频繁地切换状态，对吧，那么什么适合我们的投影矩阵呢
so that we don't need to switch states as often things like culling, right, so what fits into our frustum
也许还有某种遮挡剔除，这些系统同样与特定的渲染接口无关
maybe some kind of occlusion culling as well, those systems, again, have nothing to do with specific render apis
我们必须为每一个渲染接口执行这些操作，所以为什么不让渲染器处理那些呢
we have to do them for every single render api, so why not just have, like why does, why not just have the renderer handle that, right
材质，因此材质与着色器紧密相关，材质本质上是什么
materials, so materials are very closely tied with shaders, essentially what a material is
只是一个着色器加上一些统一的数据，从那里
is just a shader plus some uniform data, and from there
我们可能会有一些类似于材质实例的东西，它们是基于材质的
we'll probably have things like material instances, which are based on materials
那通常是大多数渲染器和引擎的运行方式，但那也是在这里实现的
that's typically how most renderers and most engines kind of work, but again that's something that is implemented here
所以有客户端统一存储，然后有一个着色器链接，以及所有那些东西
so having like client side uniform storage, and then a shader linked, and all of that stuff
那适用于每个渲染接口，没有什么不同，而纹理或顶点缓冲区之类的东西
that's that applies to every single render api, that's not different, whereas something like a texture or a vertex buffer
你们知道每个渲染接口可能会有所不同，这就是为什么我们需要在这里而不是在这里
you know might be different per render api, which is why we needed to be here and not here
对吧，希望这有意义，至于LOD，对吧，层次细节，所以我们的测量质量较低，测量量较小
right, hopefully this is making some sence, lod, right, level of detail, so measures that we have lower quality and kind of smaller measures
本质上，在多边形计数和三角形计数方面，我们决定渲染一些东西
essentially in terms of polygon count and triangle count the further away, we decide to render something
因此，我们不会像那样渲染那么多三角形系统
so that we don't render as many triangles systems like that
也不会渲染实际渲染接口动画中的三角形系统
not something that belongs in the actual render api animation as well
它有点像客户端渲染器，它的实现不需要任何实际的渲染接口支持相机，对吧
it's purely kind of like a client side renderer, implementation of that doesn't need any actual render api support cameras, right
再说一次，你们知道的，我们需要比如相机可能被绑定到帧缓冲上
again something that is just you know we need to like maybe a camera might be tied to a frame buff
或者相机可能正在渲染到渲染目标，对吧
or maybe a camera might be rendering to a render target, right
在渲染器端实现的这种东西不需要是其中的一部分
that kind of stuff implemented on the renderer side doesn't need to be part of that
我的意思是，实际上渲染通道几乎也属于这里
I mean in fact render passes almost belong here as well
之所以把它们放在这，是因为它们可以被视为图元
the reason I put them here is because they can be seen as a primitive
它们在不同的渲染接口中实现的方式不同，但一般来说，你们知道我们是否想要控制
and they are implemented differently in different render apis, but in general, you know if we want to control
就像我们想再次开始或结束渲染通道一样，在实际的渲染器中也会有一个接口，即视觉效果
like if we want to begin or end a render pass again, there will be an api for that in the actual renderer as well, visual effects
所以像粒子系统这样的东西也是，现在这些东西产生了这些东西，不要误会我
so things like particle systems, that stuff as well is, now that stuff made this stuff don't get me wrong
将需要渲染接口的支持我在这里没有列出的东西，例如批处理或实例，对吧
will require support from render api things I didn't list here, things like batching for example or Instancing, right
批处理通常可以由渲染端控制，而实例化需要渲染接口支持
batching is something that you usually can be controlled by the render side, whereas instancing requires render api support
所以，诸如此类的事情突然间决定要批量处理一些东西，但你们想使用实例
so things like that suddenly you decide you want to batch something, but you want to use instancing
在这种情况下，那需要在这里的接口中设置实例，但可以从渲染器中使用
in this case, that requires instancing to be kind of set up in the api here, but then can be used from the renderer
所以那也是需要考虑的，至于PostFX，我指的是一个后期效果系统，对吧
so that's something to think about as well, PostFX, and by that I mean specifically a post effects system, right
所以实际上，如果你们分解了后期效果是什么，我们将场景渲染到帧缓冲区
so actually if you break down what post effects is, we render our scene to a frame buffer
然后我们使用个不同的着色器在屏幕上渲染四边形，使用顶点缓冲区，这里应用了PostFX
and then we use a different shader to just render a quad on the screen, using a vertex buffer with kind of our PostFX applied here
但你们也知道，对于PostFX，通常我们可能需要额外的数据，而这些数据不是立即需要的
but also you know, for PostFX, it's common that we might need additional data that we wouldn't need immediately
例如，一个非常简单的PostFX可能类似于颜色校正，那很容易，因为我们该怎么做
so for example, a very simple PostFX might be something like a color correction, that's easy, because well what do we do
将场景渲染到帧缓冲区，然后再次渲染该帧缓冲区，在另一个四边形上使用不同的着色器
we render our scene to a frame buffer, and then we render that frame buffer again, using a different shader onto another quad
然后在屏幕上显示，然后着色器可能会进行颜色校正
and then display that on our screen, and then that shader might do the color correction
然而，如果我们想做一些像屏幕空间环境光遮蔽之类的效果
whereas if we want to do something like screen space ambient occlusion
对吧，效果不是很好，但我们还是继续吧
right, not a great effect, but let's just go with it
我们需要原始渲染通道中的一些其他数据，例如位置法线数据，对吧
we need some other data from our original render pass, such as like positional normal data, right
我们希望这些法线像一个单独的缓冲区一样进入，这样就可以在PostFX着色器中读取它们
we want those normals into like a separate buffer, so we can then read them in our PostFX shader
因为我们需要在运行PostFX之前不需要的额外信息，所以诸如此类的事情，对吧
because we need that extra information that we didn't need before we ran that PostFX, so things like that, right
所以它是一种结合在一起的方式，具体来说，我指的是PostFX系统
so it's kind of it does tie in together, as specifically I do mean as PostFX system
它可能处理那些渲染通道的方式
the way that it might handle those render passes
我们需要的这些额外数据通常是由渲染器实现的
and those additional data that we need is something that typically would be implemented by the renderer
因为这个渲染使用我们创建的接口，所以它不需要专门使用OpenGL
because this render uses this api that we've created, just so that it doesn't need to use OpenGL specifically
或者任何实际的渲染接口，我希望你们知道我说的是哪种渲染接口
or any actual render api specifically, I hope you guys know which render api I'm talking about
当我说渲染接口时，有时我在谈论这个列表，有时我在谈论OpenGL Vulcan之类的东西
when I just say render api, sometimes I'm talking about this list, sometimes I'm talking about OpenGL Vulcan that kind of thing
但希望它能让其他事情变得有意义，所以我想，你们知道，就像
but hopefully it is to make sense other things, so I think, you know like
我猜随机技术，比如反射，环境光遮蔽，你们知道，用类似反射探测器的方式设置反射
I guess random techniques like reflections, ambient occlusion, you know setting up reflections in terms of like reflection probes
你们知道渲染是为了比如立方体贴图，比如环境光遮蔽，无论是PostFX还是更高级的效果
you know rendering to like cube maps doing things like ambient occlusion, whether that being a PostFX or like kind of more advanced
你们知道HBAO(水平环境光遮蔽)或其他我们可用的渲染技术
you know HBAO or whatever other other kind of render techniques we have available to us
那些东西通常在渲染器中实现，那是我们在那里做的事情
those things are typically implemented in the renderer, that's something that we do there
因为我们不会，比如有时我们可能需要额外的接口支持，但是如果你们考虑一下
because we don't like sometimes we might need extra api support, but if you think about it
通常，我们应该能够使这个接口非常强大，不需要突然实现
usually we should be able to get this api pretty strong to the point, where we don't need to suddenly implement
就像每次我们想做的时候实际渲染接口中更细粒度的东西一样，就像一种不同的技术，对吧
like finer grain things inside the actual render api every time we want to do, like a different technique, right
现在我想说的是，这次测试之所以变得困难，是因为这看起来
now I do want to say though that the reason this test become difficult is because as nice as this might seem
就像我们可以有一个渲染接口，对吧，那看起来很棒
like we can just have a render api, right, that seems great
就像我们有一个渲染接口，我们让它非常强大，它可以处理所有事情
like we have a render api, we make it really strong, it handles everything
突然，每当我想在渲染器中执行任何操作时，我都必须编写一次
suddenly every time I wanna do anything in my renderer, I have to write it once
它只会在我们支持的每个渲染器接口上运行，这是一个伟大的梦想，但在实践中
and it'll just work on every renderer ip how we support, that's a great dream to have, but in practice
那通常不是一种非常优化的方式，原因是如果你们尝试开发一个通用渲染接口
that's usually not a very optimized way of doing things, the reason is that if you try and make a generalist render api
你们有同样的问题，就像你们尝试做一个通用游戏引擎一样，对吧
you have the same problems as if you try and make a generalist game engine, right
这是一个可以用于任何游戏的游戏引擎，你们可以想到，你们可以使用这个游戏引擎
it's a game engine that can be used for any game, you can think of, you can make with this game engine
但是如果我为我的特定游戏编写特定引擎，那会更好吗？不，不会更好
but is that gonna be better than if I have a, if I write my own specific engine for my specific game, no, it's not gonna be better
这就是开始变得危险的地方，因为理想情况下，如果你们学习了高级的技术
which is where this starts to become dangerous, because ideally speaking, like if you get into advanced techniques
那确实需要更高的性能，你们是否能够编写一个通用接口并使用它
that actually do require more performance, are you going to be able to write a generalist api, and use that
如果你们直接使用原始DirectX12，则可以获得与你们相同的性能级别和优化效果
and receive the same level of performance, and just optimization as you are, if you just use raw DirectX12 directly
当然不是，对吧，所以你们必须非常小心，我们会遇到这样的事情
of course not, right, so you have to really be careful with this, and we'll kind of as we go along, we'll kind of run into stuff like this
并且可能会进行一些认真的讨论，甚至可能喜欢以一种方式实施一些事情，然后很好地
and have probably some serious discussions, and may even like implement things one way and then be like well
事实上，这并没有我周末做的其他测试那么好，结果更好，我们可能会重新开始
actually this isn't as good as other tests I did over the weekend, and it turned out to be better, and we might go back on that
我不知道，总的来说应该很有趣，但我只是想提醒你们，不要有一些潜在的问题
and I don't know, generally should be pretty fun, but I'm just kind of warning you guys off some potential problems
那将不可避免地从这样的事情中产生，好吧，记住这一点，我没有提到的一件事
that will inevitably arise from stuff like this, okay, so with that in mind, one of the things that I didn't mention
我们还必须设计一个渲染指令队列，对吧
which we will also have to pretty much design is essentially a render command queue, right
这种联系类似于告诉渲染接口正确操作的渲染器和指令之间的联系，对吧，渲染指令队列
and this kind of ties in like between the renderer telling the render api what to do right and a render command queue
基本上是一种将每个渲染指令编码为一个大缓冲区的方法
is just basically a way for us to encode every single render command into like a big buffer
所以每帧一次，当我们决定从本质上渲染所有内容时，我们会通过那个指令队列
so that once per frame when we actually decide to like render everything essentially, we go through that command queue
我们执行所有这些命令，通常数据都是在线的，如果需要，我们可以在不同的线程上运行它
and we execute all those commands, and typically the data is all in line, we can run it on a different thread if we want to
与专用的渲染线程不同，因此当它在某种程度上通过渲染队列时，我们可以做其他事情
unlike a dedicated render thread, so that while it's kind of going through that render queue, we could be doing other stuff
比如为下一帧提交更多渲染指令，或者在主线程上执行游戏逻辑或接口，或者其他任何操作
like submitting more render commands for the next frame, or doing game logic or doing ai, or anything else on our kind of main thread
所以那就是渲染指令队列，你们知道的
so that's a render command queue, you know
像Vulcan这样的接口有指令队列，对吧，那就是你们在Vulcan中所做的
an api like Vulcan has command queue, right, that's what you do in Vulcan
你们有很多指令，比如，你们知道绑定这个，然后绘制这个三角形，然后你们知道
you kind of you have a bunch of commands like for example, you know bind this and then draw this triangle, and then you know
这是我的场景状态，这是视口状态，你们要做的是把所有这些都放到一个队列中
this is my scenes state, this is my viewport state, and what you do is you put all of that into a like into a queue essentially
最后你们告诉Vulcan，我要你们实际给出那个队列，对吧，我要你实际通过那个队列
and then eventually you tell Vulcan, I want you to actually present that queue, right, I want you to actually go through that queue
然后进行渲染，那么Vulcan就有那个，但OpenGL没有，所以我们需要为OpenGL创建
and then do that rendering thing,  so Vulcan has that, but OpenGL doesn't, so we need to create that for OpenGL
一般来说，如果你们可以选择比如，好了，我想实现三个接口，我应该如何制作它们
and just in general if you have like a choice of like okay, I want to implement three apis, what do I make them
就像通常的选择一样，我会让它们像DirectX一样
like usually the choices I'll make them like DirectX
对吧，因为DirectX对我来说至少是最明智的实际接口，对吧
right, because DirectX like for me at least seems to be the most sensible actual api, right
所以我们可能会遵循这种设计，但因为我喜欢做新东西，因为Hazel对我来说是一个新项目
so we might follow that kind of design, but because I like making new things, and because Hazel is a new project for me
我可以试着做我自己的东西，然后我们看看会发生什么
I might just try and make my own thing, and we'll see what happens
并且那就是我们作为一个社区一起工作的地方
and that's where we as a community we work together
我们试着做一些新的东西，很酷的东西，所以只需要给你们一些内在的东西
and we try and build something, new as something cool, so just giving you guys a little bit of inside there
那么我们从哪里开始谈很好，但我们需要真正开始这件事，那么要怎么做呢
so where do we start talking is great, but we need to actually start this thing, so how are we going to do that
首先我们要从OpenGL开始，现在我要从OpenGL开始
well first of all we're gonna start with OpenGL, now would I start with OpenGL
如果我只是为了好玩而制作自己的引擎，而没有用它制作视频系列，可能不会
if I was just making my own engine like for fun without making a video series out of it, probably not
老实说，可能根本不支持OpenGL，直接从Vulcan开始
probably wouldn't support OpenGL at all, to be honest, just start with like Vulcan maybe
但问题是OpenGL是最简单的接口，需要从外部进行更强大的设计才能使其真正发挥作用
but the problem is OpenGL is the simplest and the easiest api, requires a bit of a stronger design from outside to make it actually good
但这是最简单的接口，对吧，我们需要那个，因为这是一个游戏引擎系列，图形系列
but it's the simplest and easiest thing, right, we want that because this is a game engine series, an unnaturally graphics series
很明显，我对图形感兴趣，我喜欢图形，因为老实说，这是我最喜欢的部分
I am obviously having interested in graphics and I love graphics, since my favorite part of this whole thing to be honest
但我承认这是一个游戏引擎，我们有两个目标，首先，我们想尽快在屏幕上看到东西
but I do recognize this is a game engine, we have kind of two goals, first of all, we want to see stuff on the screen as soon as possible
并尽快在屏幕上看到美丽的东西，因为这样才能真正看到结果
and see beautiful things on the screen as soon as possible, because that's going to be great to actually see results
很明显，你们中的很多人都想要结果，因为这是一个YouTube系列，在这种情况下必须很好
and obviously a lot of you guys actually want results, because this is a YouTube series, and it has to be fine in that case
而且它必须有市场，从我的角度来看，我也必须能够用
and it has to be marketable, from my point of view as well, I have to be able to make pretty thumbnails with like
嘿，看看Hazel引擎，看起来很棒，即使我选择了像Vulcan这样的东西，架构可能会很神奇
hey, look Hazel engine, looks great, even though if I chose something like Vulcan, the architecture might be amazing
我们可能已经做了大量的代码工作，但有什么好看的东西要展示吗？没有，所以有这一面
we might have done a lot of code work, but do we have anything pretty to show not really, so there's that side
另一方面，我们不想花两年的时间来实现渲染接口，我们想在运行中有所收获
and the other side is we don't want to spend two years implementing rendering apis, we want to get something up on running
然后转到其他场景，如场景系统或级别编辑，如工具集或序列化
and then move on to something else like a scene like a scene system or like a level edited like tool set or like sterilization and
像那样的数据，或者实际的逻辑和脚本，或者像一个空的组件系统
like data like that, or actual logic and scripting, or like an empty component system
我们需要处理这么多其他系统
we have so many other systems we need to deal with
因此，使用我们的OpenGL并不理想，但它可以完成工作
so using our OpenGL is not ideal, but it will get the job done
对吧，不是以最好的方式，也不是最快的方式
right, not in the best way possible, not in the fastest way possible
但它会完成工作，因此我们的第一步是构建渲染接口部分
but it will get the job done, so our step one with that is to build that render api part
所以当我谈到这一点以及所有这些事情时
so when I talked about this and all of these things
那就是我们开始的地方，构建那些东西，一旦完成了，就开始构建另一个，那就是渲染器
that's what we begin with, we build that stuff, once we've done that, we build the other side which is the renderer
当然，这些是有重叠的，它们不是相互依赖的，对吧
of course these do have overlap, they're not dependent on each other, right
例如，我们不需要在开始渲染器之前完成渲染接口
so for example, we don't need the render api to be complete before we can begin the renderer
一旦我们在渲染接口中有足够的内容来绘制三角形，猜猜我们将要做什么
once we have enough in the render api to like draw a triangle, guess what we're going to do
我们将编写一个渲染器，可以绘制三角形
we're going to write a renderer that can draw a triangle
好了，这样我们就可以开始运行这些东西，然后就对其进行迭代
okay, so that we get that stuff up and running, and then we'll iterate over it
我们会根据需要添加更多的东西，你们知道
and we'll add more things as we need them, you know
突然之间，我们希望能够渲染到纹理或类似的东西
suddenly, we want to be able to render to a texture or something like that
我们将在纹理目标、纹理渲染目标接口中添加帧缓冲区，好吧
we'll add the frame buffer in the texture target, texture render target api at that point, okay
在那之后，我们有了一个基础来渲染我们想要的任何东西
after that we have a base to render anything we want
对吧，当然，通过构建渲染器，我说的是
right, and of course by build renderer I am talking about things like
我们需要建立一个材质系统，也许像着色器的阴影一样，那将基本上包括在第二步中
we need to build a material system, maybe like a shader of paza stuff like that, that will be kind of included in step two essentially
但在那之后，我们可以渲染我们想要的任何东西，你们知道我们想要像
but after that we can render anything we want, you know we want to render like
一些很酷的东西，比如pbr材料，3d模型等等，我们可以，我们应该能够处理
some cool like pbr materials and like 3d models and all that kind of stuff, we can, we should be able to
所以，一旦我们在OpenGL中完成了这项工作
so once we can do that once in OpenGL
我就可以像一个完整的3D场景一样渲染，看起来很美
I can render like a full 3D scene, that looks beautiful
好吧，可能还有PostFX和所有这些东西，那就是我们现在要实现其他接口的时候了
right, with probably PostFX and all of that stuff, that's when we're going to implement other apis now this is
我写这些是为了做决定，因为正如我所说的，我们可能想做一些像场景这样的事情
and I did write to be decided, because as I said, we probably want to do things like a scene
你们知道场景序列化，我在组件系统中提到的所有其他东西
you know scene level letter to sterilization, all that other stuff I mentioned in component system
在我们开始深入其他接口之前，编写所有我们可能想做的事情，但这是为你们准备的系列
scripting all that stuff we probably want to do before we start diving into other apis, but this is a series for you guys
如果你们决定了，你们知道我们有足够的东西，让我们实现Vulcan，我真的很想了解这一点
if you guys decide that, you know we've got enough stuff, let's just implement Vulcan, and I really want to learn about that
如果大多数人决定，我就会去实现那个，对吧，老实说，我很乐意做那个
if the majority of people decide that, that I'm gonna do that, right, I would love to do that to be honest
但我只是在想大多数人想要什么，很明显，我想让这个系列成为你们喜欢的东西
but I'm just thinking about what the majority of people want, and obviously trying to make this series something that you guys enjoy
还有一些东西比如，特别是比如赞助人真正想看到的东西，但不仅仅是赞助人
and something that like, especially like the patrons actually want to see, but not just patrons
别那么想，我只关心那些在经济上支持我的人，显然我是关心我所有的观众的
don't think that, I'm just only care about people who support me financially, obviously I care about all of my viewers
但我想，支持我的好处之一当然是，你可以把这部系列更多地引导到你们真正想要的地方
but of course one of the perks of supporting me, I guess, is that you get to steer this series a little bit more into where you actually want
但是，所以DirectX11和12，Metal之类的东西，我最终会得到的
but yeah so DirectX 11 and 12, Metal that kind of stuff that I will get to that eventually
但这是我首先想要的东西，对吧
but this is kind of the stuff I want first, right
我们要从最简单的接口开始，我们要做，我们要做一些看起来很漂亮的东西
we're gonna start with the simplest api possible, and we're gonna make, we're gonna make something that looks pretty
如果我们有时间和资源做类似的事情，我们可以继续做其他事情
and then after we have that, we can move on to other stuff, if we kind of have the time and resources to do something like that
好了，就这么多了，谢谢你们观看，希望你们喜欢这个视频
okay, so that's pretty much it, thanks for watching guys, hope you enjoy this video
如果你们喜欢的话，就为它点赞吧
if you did, and hit that like button
你们还可以帮助支持patreon上的系列，正如我在整个视频中提到的那样
you can also help support the series on patreon as I've mentioned throughout this video
我想说的是，就像这是一个巨大的旅程，这将需要我们一段时间
I do want to say that like this is a big journey, this is something that's gonna take us a while
OpenGL非常简单，在很多情况下，它也是，因为它非常简单，在很多情况下它也会很烦人
OpenGL very vs, it's very simple, in a lot of cases, it's also, because it's so simple, it can also be annoying in a lot of cases
但我想我们会过得很轻松，所以我不太担心那类事情的实际细节
but I think we're gonna have a generally easy time with that, so I'm not too worried about the actual details about like about that kind of stuff
我们应该尽快启动并运行，我认为这是一个很好的机会
we should get something up and running pretty quickly, I would think this is a good opportunity
要查看我的OpenGL系列，如果你们还没有，这里有一个大约20个播放列表，我想还有视频
to check out my OpenGL series, if you haven't already, there's a playlist of like 20, I think also videos
那将涵盖很多这些图元，我想我不知道，是的，我没有进入像帧缓冲区这样的高级领域
that will kind of cover a lot of these primitives, I don't think I got it, yeah I didn't get into like advanced things like frame buffers
不，那是特别高级的，但我没有做到那个，我不认为或者你们知道渲染一个目标
not, that's particularly advanced, but I didn't get to things like that, I didn't think or you know render a target
所以我喜欢很多这样的东西，我可能最终会在那个系列中
so I just like a lot of that kind of stuff, I probably will eventually in that series
我想我要做的是展示一个实现，比如，嘿，你们知道我们需要在Hazel中设置帧缓冲区类
I think what I'll do is I'll show an implementation of like, hey, you know we need to riot frame buffer class in Hazel
让我们那样做吧，然后我将链接到OpenGL系列
let's just do that, but then I'll link to an OpenGL series
我将制作一段关于帧缓冲区的视频，它实际上讨论了帧缓冲区在OpenGL中的运行方式
video that I'll make about frame buffers where it actually talks about, how frame buffers work in OpenGL
所以我可能会，我可能会继续OpenGL系列的很多内容，因为我们在整个过程中都有所进展
so I'll probably be, I'll probably resume the OpenGL series a lot, as we kind of move throughout this
下个周末，通常是我拍视频的时候，是我的单身派对，因为正如我在之前的视频中提到的
now next weekend, which is usually when I make videos is my bachelor party, because as I mentioned in the previous video
我现在还不到一个月就要结婚了，所以我下周末不能拍视频了
I'm getting married in less than a month now, so because of that, I'm not gonna be able to make a video next weekend
我希望你们能理解，我的意思是
I hope you guys understand, I mean
如果你们知道我在这份全职工作和其他事情上试图平衡我的生活
if you know trying to balance my life in this full time job and other stuff's going on
这只是我的脑袋在爆炸，所以正如我所提到的，这又是一个回去观看OpenGL系列的好时机
it's just my head's exploding, so this is again as I mentioned, a good time to go back and watch that OpenGL series
甚至可以自己尝试实现一个渲染器，对吧，尝试找到我在设计中概述的那些东西
and maybe even try and implement a renderer yourself, right, try and find those things that I've outlined in the design
然后使用你们创建的接口，这种特定于OpenGL的，或者更确切地说是与平台无关的
and then with that api that you've created, this OpenGL specific or rather platform agnostic kind of
尝试然后使用该接口实际绘制三角形，那是一个非常好的起点，当然可以
try and then use that api to actually draw a triangle, that's a really good place to start, of course you can
如果你们看OpenGL系列，就可以绘制一个三角形，所以那是我的家庭作业
you will be able to draw a triangle, if you watch that OpenGL series, so that's kind of my homework
比如我想让你们做的，而我下周有点自吹自擂的习惯，然后我们会重新开始
and my like what I want you guys to do, while I kind of have this habits brag next week, and then we'll just get back into it
老实说，我真的很期待，所以我希望你们喜欢这期视频，下期见
and to be honest, I'm really looking forward to it, so I hope you guys enjoyed this video, and I'll see you next time, goodbye